《星際迷航: 新世界》前情提要
Previously on Star Trek: Strange New Worlds...
史波克 這是詹姆斯·柯克
Spock, meet James Kirk,
法拉格特號的大副
first officer of the Farragut.
當年我剛接受任命時
When I took my commission,
跟著派克學習了一週
I spent a week shadowing Pike.
那段經歷讓我受益匪淺
It made all the difference.
你知道幾乎永生
You want to know the worst thing
這件事最糟糕的一點是什麼嗎
about living almost forever?
你會失去你愛的人
The loss of those you love.
這不是你的錯 克里斯
It wasn't your fault, Chris.
我是領隊人
I led the mission.
我們得對別人的生命負責
We're responsible for other people's lives.
船員們的性命就是我的一切
The lives of my crew mean everything to me.
我們的職業讓我們不得不頻繁的面對死亡
Our job puts us up against death
這本就不公平
more than is fair.
你可以選擇讓死亡贏過你
Now, you can let death win
又或是挺身反擊它
or you can fight back.
大副私人日誌 星曆
First officer's personal log. Stardate...
星曆到底是怎麼算的
What is the stardate?
日子全都混淆在一起了
They're all blending together.
法拉格特號正在聯邦星域外
Farragut is conducting a planetary survey
對一顆無人居住的M級星球 赫利孔γ星
of Helicon Gamma, an uninhabited M-class world
進行行星勘測
outside Federation space, and...
而我實在是無聊極了
...I am so deeply bored.
我發現最近總是忍不住質疑
I find myself constantly questioning
維瑞爾艦長的命令
Captain V'Rel's orders.
對於風險 她避之唯恐不及
It's like she's allergic to risk.
我們在宇宙裡是要幹實事的
We're out here to get our hands dirty,
是來探索的
to be explorers,
而不是對著掃描數據三重核查 紙上談兵
not to triple-check every sensor reading.
我明白
I get it.
她想嚴格按照規定來辦事
She wants to do everything by the book.
昨天晚上到現在有什麼變化嗎
Any changes since last night?
我只是覺得如果規定是我定的
I just think the book would be more interesting
事情會變得更有趣一些
if I got to write it.
舵手
Helm,
帶我們去北部大陸上空的
bring us into a low geosynchronous orbit
近地同步軌道
over the northern continent.
維瑞爾艦長
Captain V'Rel, if I may,
如果我們能再靠近一點的話
we could get much more detailed readings
就能得到更多更具體的數據了
from an even lower orbit.
你說的是多近
How low do you suggest?
最近的那種
Lowest orbit there is.
親自踏上星球的土地
Our boots on the ground.
考慮到地質不穩定的因素
Given the geological instability,
這樣做會帶來不必要的風險
it seems an unwarranted risk.
我們來就是為了風險的 不是嗎
Risk is why we're here, isn't it?
不然星際艦隊只要發一顆探測器過來就好了
Starfleet could have sent a probe,
但是他們讓我們來了
but instead they sent us
因為有些事必須要我們親眼所見
because some things you need to see for yourself
-才能真正理解 -艦長
- to truly understand. - Captain,
剛剛有一股未知的力量撞到了
an unknown force just impacted
赫利孔γ星的地表
Helicon Gamma's surface.
報告
Report.
檢測到行星地殼發生地震波擾動
There's a seismic disturbance in the planet's crust.
紅色警報
Red alert.
舵手 規避機動
Helm, take evasive action.
全體船員 做好衝擊準備
All hands, brace for...
醫療團隊馬上到艦橋
Medical team to the bridge.
這裡是聯邦星艦法拉格特號
This is the USS Farragut.
我們需要緊急援助 我們遭受嚴重損傷
We need immediate assistance. We've taken heavy...
長官 有什麼東西在干擾我們的通訊信號
Sir, something's interfering with the comms signal.
我正在嘗試識別其來源
I'm trying to identify the source.
是那玩意發出的干擾
It's coming from that.
讀數怎樣
Readings?
還有生命信號
Life signs on board,
但我們的人手只夠操作星艦的
but barely enough to crew the ship.
這麼多系統宕機
Multiple systems nonfunctioning.
看在貝爾德的份上到底怎麼回事
What in Baird's name happened here?
看在誰份上?
Whose name?
那個蘇格蘭籍的發明家
The Scottish inventor.
無人不知約翰·羅傑·貝爾德啊
Everyone knows John Logie Baird.
救援來了嗎
Rescue?
我們的確是來救援的
That is our purpose.
問題是 誰襲擊了你們
The question is: rescue from what?
我只看見了一眼 特別大的東西
I only saw a glimpse. It was huge.
他正在內出血
He's got internal bleeding.
我需要把他帶到醫務室去
I need to get him to sickbay.
我最好趕緊去輪機室
I'd better go to Engineering
去看看曲速核心怎麼樣了
and check there's still a warp core.
之後來匯報你們的發現
Report back with your findings.
我們會在艦橋
We will offer our assistance
幫助維瑞爾艦長
to Captain V'Rel on the bridge.
等等
Wait.
不光是艦對艦通訊
It's not just ship to ship.
所有的通訊都不能用了
All comms are down.
我們沒法和彼此保持聯繫
We'll have no way to get in touch with each other.
去吧
Go.
但到時候在盡快在艦橋匯合
But find your way to the bridge as soon as you can.
你給我好好撐住
Don't you shut down on me.
增援到了
Reinforcements have arrived.
你們的首席醫療官呢 少尉
Where's your CMO, Ensign?
好吧 只剩你了
Just you, then.
身上好多都是鈍器傷
I'm seeing a lot of blunt-force injuries in here.
發生了什麼
What happened?
你應該去問艦長
You should ask the captain.
她在四號床
Bed four.
維瑞爾艦長 我是查普爾護士
Captain V'Rel, I'm Nurse Chapel.
你有些腦挫傷 但沒有顱腦腫脹
You have a cerebral contusion. There's no cranial swelling.
我需要回艦橋去
I need to get back to the bridge.
嗯 等我們確定了
Mm-hmm, right after we make sure
你沒有腦疝的症狀之後再說
that your brain isn't herniating.
躺下
Stay.
我們的外勤隊已經去艦橋了
Our away team is heading to the bridge.
他們會幫忙的
They can help.
試試繞過主傳感器系統
Try bypassing primary sensors.
檢查側向陣列還有沒有未損壞的功能模塊
See if anything's functioning in the lateral array.
阿爾瓦雷斯 帶我們離開這片殘骸區
Alvarez, get us out of this debris.
長官 沒有傳感器的話太危險了
Sir, it's too dangerous without the sensors.
-艦長 -維瑞爾艦長把指揮權交給了我
- Captain... - Captain V'Rel left me the conn,
我的職責是確保船的安全
and it's up to me to return it intact.
史波克先生
Mr. Spock.
烏乎拉少尉 拉安
Ensign Uhura. La'An.
歡迎登艦
Welcome aboard.
詹姆斯
James.
你這邊的亂子真是有夠大的
Quite a mess you've gotten yourself into.
看起來這是我的專長
Seems to be my specialty.
你們能接到求救信號真是奇蹟
It's a miracle you got our distress call.
通訊都被干擾了
Signal was jammed.
信號干擾也對我們造成了嚴重的影響
The interference has wreaked havoc with us, too.
但我也許能建立一條視訊連接
But I might be able to set up line of sight.
請求借用你們的遙測儀器
Permission to borrow your telemetry?
完全可以
More than granted.
阿爾瓦雷斯 讓我們靠近進取號
Alvarez, aim us at the Enterprise.
準備聯繫艦長
Stand by for the captain.
派克艦長
Captain Pike.
鑑於目前情況十分危急
I'll dispense with the pleasantries
我就不多說客套話了
since we're still in a critical situation.
威脅目標還在當前區域嗎
Is the threat still in the area?
我不清楚
Unknown.
告訴我你知道的信息
Tell me what you do know.
我們當時正在對赫利孔γ星進行地質勘測
We were in the middle of a geological survey of Helicon Gamma
就在這時
when--
坦白說 實在無法用科學術語來描述當時的狀況
well, there's no scientific way to put it--
星球瞬間天崩地裂
all hell broke loose.
-因為星球不穩定嗎 -不是
- Planetary instability? - No.
一束聚焦的引力束瞄準了這顆行星
A focused gravitational beam aimed at the planet.
被什麼瞄準的
Aimed by what?
擁有發射功率如此強大的牽引光束
A ship capable of generating a tractor beam that
這飛船的規模恐怕
powerful would have to be...
比有記錄以來的任何星艦
Several orders of magnitude bigger
都要大上好幾個數量級
than any starship on record.
我知道這聽起來很荒謬 但這是真的
I know. It sounds crazy, but it's true.
我們差點都沒發現它 它對我們不感興趣
We barely saw it. It wasn't interested in us.
我們不過是它的連帶損傷
We were just collateral damage.
滅世者
Destroyer of Worlds.
然後它就消失了嗎
And it just disappeared?
我們撞上碎片的時候 傳感器
When the debris hit, we lost sensors,
通訊 所有重要系統都損壞了
comms, all critical systems.
維瑞爾艦長雖已受傷 但意識尚清
Captain V'Rel was injured but lucid enough
足以下達撤離指令
to give the evacuation order.
逃生艙已部署完畢
Escape pods have been deployed.
我會留下最低限度的留守人員
I'm keeping a skeleton crew aboard
盡量避免法拉格特號淪為需要打撈的廢船
so Farragut doesn't become a salvage job.
你做得很好
Well, you've performed commendably,
但還是把你們都一併救出來吧
but let's get you all to safety.
一號 讓法拉格特號的全體成員
Number One, I want all Farragut crew
立刻傳送到艦上來
beamed aboard immediately.
明白 艦長
Aye, Captain.
全員撤退 從逃生艙開始
Full evacuation. We'll start with the escape pods.
執行吧
Proceed.
派克艦長
Captain Pike...
我明白 我也不會放棄我的星艦
I know, I wouldn't want to give up my ship either,
但艦員的安全必須放在首位
but the safety of the crew has to come first.
這是正確的決定
It's the right call.
我們有嚴重受傷的患者在醫務室
We have some critically injured patients in sickbay
缺少醫生照顧
and no doctor.
烏乎拉少尉
Ensign Uhura,
跟查普爾確認哪些患者需要緊急撤離
confirm with Chapel which patients require immediate evac
然後把他們送往進取號
and get them to Enterprise.
馬上去辦 艦長
On it, Captain.
在你撤離之前
Before you evacuate,
把該未知星艦的所有戰術信息傳輸給進取號
transfer all tactical info on this mystery ship.
以防他們再次出手 我要做好充足的準備
I want to be ready if they take another swing.
我已經恢復了部分傳感器的功能
I have restored some function to sensors.
我們僅有的這點數據就交給
Sending what little data we have back
努尼恩·辛格上尉帶回
with Lieutenant Noonien-Singh.
我現在就傳送回艦 艦長
Beaming back now, Captain.
我來親自把這個交給你
I'll hand this to you personally.
開始傳送
Energize.
現在 把你們全部的系統
Now put all your systems...
烏乎拉 重新接通
Uhura, get him back.
發生什麼了
What happened?
恐怕連不上了
I don't think I can.
為什麼
Why not?
阿爾瓦雷斯 我需要你負責戰術崗位
Alvarez, I need you on tactical.
準備好所有武器
Prepare all weapons.
明白 長官
Aye, Commander.
進取號在視野內 他們正在交戰
We have visual on Enterprise. They are engaging.
用上所有的武器朝對方開火
Whatever we've got, fire at that thing.
這不合邏輯
That is illogical.
進取號的武器明顯起不到任何作用
Enterprise's weapons were clearly ineffective.
我們的瞄準系統下線了
Our targeting systems are down.
現在開火的話作用極微
Firing would serve little purpose
-並且還有可能會誤傷進取號 -那我們總得做點什麼吧
- and risk damaging Enterprise. - Well, we have to do something.
那我們總得做點什麼吧
我們不能坐著乾等著
We can't just sit here.
此刻
At present,
恐怕我們只能這麼做
I am afraid that is all we can do.
診斷 我現在就要完整的艦船診斷報告
Diagnostic. I want a complete ship diagnostic right now.
這裡有一些好消息
Uh, well, here's some good news.
我們不再受到干擾了
We're not being jammed anymore.
好的
Great.
艦橋呼叫醫務室
Bridge to sickbay.
我需要盡快和維瑞爾艦長通話
I need to speak to Captain V'Rel ASAP.
查普爾護士回報
Nurse Chapel reporting.
她需要進行緊急顱骨切除術
She required an emergency craniectomy,
而我沒有能力實施這個手術
which I'm not qualified to perform,
於是兩分鐘前
so I beamed her to the Enterprise
我已將她傳送至進取號
two minutes ago.
指揮官 你現在是法拉格特號的艦長了
Commander, you are now captain of the Farragut.
我們靜候您的命令 長官
We await your orders, sir.
有什麼你能辨別出來的嗎
Anything you recognize?
可能是克林貢的 難說
Klingon maybe. Hard to say.
這裡沒剩下多少東西能去辨別了
There's not much left to recognize.
有些看起來年頭還不小
Some of them seem ancient.
損傷報告如何
Damage report.
主動力離線 所有網絡系統都失效了
Main power's off-line, all network systems are down.
引擎 武器 內部通訊系統
Engines, weapons, internal comms.
便攜式通訊器還是不能用
Hand communicators still are not working.
太多干擾了
Too much interference.
維生系統呢
Life support?
在以最低限度工作
Working but minimal.
派一名通訊員去
Send a runner.
口頭通知艦員到星艦中部空間集中
Tell the crew to gather in central spaces.
艦體外殼附近的區域會冷死人的
Areas near the outer hull are gonna get pretty damn cold.
艦長 我們派遣到輪機部的通訊員一直沒回來
Captain, the last runner we sent to Engineering hasn't come back.
那只能假設我們已經被登艦了
Then we have to assume that we've been boarded.
法拉格特號的傳感器日誌有什麼信息
Did the Farragut's sensor logs tell us anything
能看出建造這艘船的種族嗎
about the species that built this thing?
他們的船體對於我們的傳感器來說幾乎不可穿透
Their hull is nearly impenetrable to our sensors,
但看得出來他們的科技極為先進
but it's clear they're incredibly advanced.
艦長 你聽說過阿薩斯里克嗎
Sir, have you heard of Asaasllich,
滅世者
Destroyer of Worlds?
它還有一個譯法是噬星者
It-it also translates as Astrovore.
噬星者嗎 沒聽過
Astrovore? No.
每個在偏僻的殖民地長大的孩子
Well, every child growing up
都聽說過它
on a remote colony world has.
不同的名字 但本質上是一個東西
Different names, same story.
一艘有數百年歷史的拾荒船
Scavenger ship, hundreds of years old,
在已知星域的邊緣之外游弋
prowling just beyond the edges of known space.
從各種行星以及
Consuming resources from planets
所有不幸與其相遇的艦船身上掠奪資源
and any ship unlucky enough to cross its path.
我在邊境附近任職時也聽過一個說法
I heard a version when I was posted near the border.
克林貢人稱其為查克-卡 意為湮滅者
Klingons called it Chach-Ka. "The Annihilator."
索耶上將也在他的星際製圖課上
Admiral Sawyer told a story like that
講過類似的故事
in his Stellar Cartography class.
地圖邊緣之外的怪物
The monster past the edge of the map.
無論是不是那艘傳說中的飛船
Whether or not this is that ship,
我們已經確定它是一艘拾荒船
we know it's a scavenger.
我們必須假設他們
We have to assume that their intention
也打算把進取號給撕碎
is to tear the Enterprise apart as well.
一號 我需要你和奧特加斯合作
Number One, I need you and Ortegas to find a way
找到重新讓引擎上線的方法
to get engine control back online
這樣只要我們趕去輪機室
so that when we get to Engineering
一旦阻止能量流失
and we stop the power drain,
我們就能逃跑了
we're ready to make a run for it.
代理艦長日誌
Acting captain's log.
這個稱謂讀著很奇怪
Feels strange to say that.
要不是事態這麼糟糕 我應該會很興奮吧
Under better circumstances, it would be thrilling.
我已經讓進取號的軍官們
I've asked the Enterprise officers to fill in
去各自填補艦橋上的崗位空缺
for our missing bridge crew.
但他們幾乎不了解我
But they barely know me,
而現在我卻要他們完全信任我
and now I have to ask them to trust me.
如果我是他們的話
If I were in their shoes...
暫停記錄 請進
Pause recording. Come in.
柯克艦長 我們整理了所有
Captain Kirk, we compiled all of the data
與外星飛船遭遇時獲取的數據
from our encounter with the alien vessel.
我們都知道些什麼
What do we know?
我們的傳感器無法徹底穿透其船殼
Our sensors cannot fully penetrate its hull,
因此 關於飛船的構成
so we can ascertain little of its composition,
性能或船員配置 我們基本都無法確定
capabilities or crew complement.
它的弱點呢
What about weaknesses?
根據基礎數學知識 按照它的尺寸
Fundamental math? Its size.
對於這麼大的傢伙來說
It would be hard to generate a stable warp field
要維持穩定的曲速場是很難的 對嗎
at that scale, wouldn't it?
這麼說 它應該會很慢
Well, odds are, it's slow, but...
那我們就能抓到它
But then we can catch it.
按照規定
Regulations...
按照規定 我們本該夾著尾巴
Regulations would have us tuck tail
逃回聯邦星域
and run back to Federation space.
等我們連上子空間通訊中繼
By the time we reach a subspace relay
搬到援兵的時候
and get reinforcements,
進取號早被拆成碎片了
Enterprise will have been ripped to scraps.
我們都有親友在
We all have people on...
我哥哥在那艘船上
My brother is on that ship.
您是最高級的軍官 我們都將服從您的命令
As the ranking officer, we will follow your orders.
我只是想為您提供所有的相關信息
I merely wished to provide you with all relevant information.
這些信號是尼斯湖水怪嘴裡那些
Those are the signatures
被拆解的外星飛船所留下的
from the picked-apart alien ships we saw in Nessie's gob.
把那裡放大點看 得嗎
Enhance that bit, would you?
其中的一艘是克林貢D7級戰巡
One of the vessels is a D7-class Klingon cruiser.
裡面可能有倖存者嗎
Could any of them have survived?
極其不可能
Highly unlikely.
船體裝甲板將會被拆解
The hull plating would be disassembled,
所有可呼吸空氣都會洩漏出去
venting all breathable air.
即便是克林貢人都不能殺出一條血路
Even the Klingons couldn't fight their way out.
這些拾荒者 他們從艦船上拿走中意的東西
These scavengers, they take what they please from ships--
不管艦員的死活 還要把這些技術篡改後據為己有
damn the crew-- and pervert the tech into their own.
我們沒法估量他們到底有多大能耐
We've no idea what they're capable of.
查普爾說得對
Chapel's right.
如果速度就是我們的武器 那好鋼必須用在刀刃上
If speed is our weapon, then we have to press it.
什麼速度
What speed?
恕我直言 指揮官
Uh, with all due respect, Commander--
還是 代理艦長
I mean, Acting Captain?
還是就是艦長
Is it just Captain? Uh...
長官 他們本可以輕鬆摧毀法拉格特號
Sir, they easily could've destroyed the Farragut
或是把我們塞進那該死的巨大囊袋裡擄走
or made off with us tucked in their bloody huge pouch,
但他們沒有這麼做
but they didn't.
你心裡對此有什麼推論嗎
And you have a theory as to why?
可能因為你的星艦受損太嚴重了
Because your ship's so banged up
不值得他們去偷吧
it wasn't worth stealing?
那我需要你變出個奇蹟了 斯考特先生
Well, then I need you to perform some miracles, Mr. Scott.
按順序 我們先弄引擎 再弄武器
We need engines and weapons, in that order.
明白
Aye.
把損傷修理好
Patch up the wounded.
盡快讓它們重新上線
Get them back to work as soon as you can.
我們得弄清楚
We need to figure out where
那艘拾荒船要駛向哪裡
that scavenger ship is headed
這樣才能設法快他們一步
so we can find a way to get there first.
就這樣吧 讓我們開工
That's it. Let's get going.
真是懷念渦輪電梯啊
Really missing the turbolift.
沒事 就剩八層甲板兩條梯子要爬了
Only eight decks and two access ladders left to go.
哦不 別開槍
Oh! Oh, no, don't shoot.
人活了五千年可不是為了挨槍子的
You don't live to be 5,000 by getting yourself shot a lot.
我們正在前往輪機艙的路上
We're on our way to Engineering.
這可不興去了 除非你想
Bad place to be right now unless you're fond
被自己汩汩湧出的鮮血嗆死
of choking to death on your own gurgling blood.
怎麼會這樣
Wh... From what?
都怪那條臍帶
The umbilical!
跟著我 來
Come with me. Come.
那裡瀰漫著有毒氣體
It's flooded with toxic gas.
它直接穿透了我們的船體
It's tunneled straight through our hull.
它已經接入了我們的動力系統
It's tapped into our power systems,
計算機網絡和燃料貯箱
our computer network, our fuel storage.
我們連輔助動力都沒剩多少
We've barely any auxiliary power left.
如果我們不想法把它斷掉
If we don't disconnect it,
就沒有足夠的動力來逃脫了
we will not have enough to escape.
既然空氣是有毒的 我們需要戴上呼吸器
If the air is toxic, we'll need breathers
才能接近臍帶
to get close to the umbilical.
拿上東西 米勒少尉會護衛你們的隊伍
Grab them. Ensign Miller will escort your team.
我們擺脫了那東西的那一刻
The second we disconnect from that thing,
就要馬上準備好逃離
we need to be ready to fly.
是 艦長
Yes, Captain.
對 給我聽著
Yeah, you heard right.
你最好給我管用 你這小破玩意
You better start doing your job, you daft piece of...
斯科特先生
Mr. Scott?
一切進展順利嗎
Everything okay in there?
會的會的 只要我先拆幾個東西出來
Soon will be, once I've torn a few things out
然後再把它們裝回去
and put them back proper.
然後 這需要多久
An-And how long will that take?
正常的做法嗎 兩天
To do it right? Two days.
唔
Hmm.
要不你先這樣 先確保
Why don't you start with doing it the way
我們不會立即散架爆炸
where we won't immediately explode,
然後再在此基礎上做點別的
and we'll take it from there?
史波克和烏乎拉有突破了
Spock and Uhura made a breakthrough.
哦 是嗎 哎喲
Oh, aye? Oh.
這艘拾荒船在赫利孔γ星
The mineral that the scavenger ship was collecting
收集的礦物是奧登金
at Helicon Gamma-- it was aldentium.
哦我聽過
Oh, I've heard of it.
有幾個種族把它用在推進系統上
A few species use it in their... propulsion systems.
附近還有另一顆擁有大量礦藏的行星
There's another world nearby with significant deposits--
沙利文星 就在他們的路線上
Sullivan's Planet-- directly in their path.
有人居住嗎
Inhabited?
超過一億人口
Over a hundred million people.
而且是曲速前文明 所以還有不干涉原則
Pre-warp, so the non-interference directive
意味著我們不能直接警告他們
means we can't warn them.
不過我們也沒別的手段做些什麼
Not that there's anything we could do anyway.
但聽著 我們一定要比他們先到那裡
Listen, we need to get there first.
給拾荒船設個埋伏
Set a trap for the scavengers.
你不會是覺得 在他們搶跑了這麼久之後
You're not asking me to warp us past them,
我還能讓咱們趕到他們前頭去吧
with the head start they've got?
這樣 恢復曲速動力我沒問題
Look, I can give us warp power,
但如果你覺得這東西
but if you think this tub will hold together
都被砸成這樣了 在高曲速下還能不散架
at high speed after the beating she just took,
還是少做白日夢了
your bum's out the window.
等離子導管都
The plasma manifolds...
我理解
I understand.
我不覺得你理解
No, I'm not sure you do.
你拿到了個爛攤子 對吧
You were handed a raw deal, all right?
沒人會指責你搞砸了什麼
No one can fault you for that.
但如果我們把這艘船推得太猛 把她弄散架了
But if we push this ship too hard and it fails,
那就是我們的問題了
that's our fault, not theirs.
這是風險
It's a risk.
但我把賭注壓在我們自己身上
But I am betting on us.
準備進入最高曲速
Prepare for maximum warp.
怎麼了
What's the problem?
我剛剛繞開了所有安全措施
I just bypassed every safety feature
建立了與艦舵控制的直接連接
to make a direct connection to the helm controls.
我本該立即被電得魂飛魄散的
I should've shocked the bejesus out of myself.
沒把自己炸得灰頭土臉你還失望了嗎
Disappointed you didn't set your hair on fire?
如果剩餘的電力連讓我觸電都做不到
If there's not enough power to do that,
那就更不夠驅動星艦轉向了
there's nowhere near enough to steer the ship.
這聲音是好跡象嗎
That's a good sound, right?
這船不會叫得很開心吧
The ship is happy screaming?
是提醒我們動作要快點了
It's a reminder to work faster.
我們能人工點火推力器嗎
Can we fire the thrusters manually?
呃 如果我們想死得痛快的話 可以
I mean, we can if we want to very quickly die.
機動推力器使用化學反應點火
The maneuvering thrusters use a chemical reaction.
它們可以手動觸發
They can be triggered by hand.
但沒有通訊 我們就無法協調推力器的工作
But with no comms, we'd have no way to coordinate them.
沒有傳感器 我們就只能完全盲飛
With no sensors, we'd be flying literally blind.
為什麼要傳感器 我們可以自己看
Who needs sensors? We have eyes.
別忘了也沒有護盾和偏導儀
Add to that no shields or navigational deflector.
只要我們犯點錯誤
If we make a mistake,
而且這個情況下肯定會
which we definitely would,
我們就要變成艙壁上的一團黑炭了
we end up a scorch mark on the wall.
通訊問題嗎
Communication issue?
那我來得正好
I got here just in time, then.
這可能是第一次
This may be the first time I'm glad
我慶幸自己在1980年代生活過
to have lived through the 1980s.
艦長
Captain.
它直接連在了我們的電網上
It is hooked directly into our power grid,
我們的計算機系統上 還有燃料吊艙上
our computer systems, and our fuel pods.
可以嘗試用相位槍切斷它
We could try to sever it with our phasers.
釋放出的能量會炸掉半艘船的
That much energy would take out half the ship.
找掩護
Cover!
我不覺得他們能透過煙霧看清我們
I don't think they can see us through the smoke.
快把她帶出去
Let's get her out of here.
烏乎拉 情況報告
Uhura, status.
接近曲速七級 艦長
Approaching warp seven, sir.
行吧 雖然這船現在基本是拿膠帶黏起來的
Well, Farragut may be held together by duct tape
但只要沒散架就行
at this point, but as long as it holds...
傳感器顯示我們已經超越拾荒船了
Sensors indicate we have overtaken the scavenger vessel.
幹得不錯 各位
Excellent work, everyone.
我們還有多久抵達沙利文星
How long until we reach Sullivan's Planet?
兩個小時 如果能保持當前速度的話
Two hours, if we can maintain this speed.
如果之前有任何人跟我說 這是不可能的
I will be accepting drinks in the galley
一會都得來餐廳請我幾杯酒
from everyone who said that this was impossible.
當然 是在我們把你們的船救出來之後
After we have saved your ship, of course.
當然
Of course.
報告
Report.
我們掉出了曲速
Well, we've dropped out of warp,
並且失去了所有引擎動力
and I've lost all engine power.
艦長 按照計劃 現在我們
Captain, our stratagem has put us
直接位於拾荒船前方的路徑上
directly in the path of the scavenger vessel.
我很清楚 史波克
I am aware, Spock.
我跟你說過的 等離子導管全炸開花了
It's the plasma manifolds-- they've blown out.
那就想盡一切辦法
Well, then take whoever you need
用你能用的一切資源和人力去修
and get down there and fix them.
它們直接炸沒了 沒法修了
They are gone! Beyond repair!
我們現在得進船塢
We'll need to put into spacedock now
才能更換它們了
and replace them.
我們 我們把她推得太猛了
We just... we pushed her too hard.
現在只能坐以待斃了
We're dead in the water.
我告訴過你了 我檢查過讀數了
I told you, I rechecked the numbers
而且檢查了三次 三次都告訴我
and re-rechecked them, and all three times confirmed
現在曲速引擎就是個超大號鎮紙 什麼用也不頂了
the warp engines are now giant paperweights.
我們還有一部分脈衝動力
We still have some impulse power.
但也不夠
Not nearly enough.
我看我們能做的就是裝死
I'm afraid all we can do is play dead
希望拾荒船能再次忽略我們
and hope the scavenger ignores us.
有可能他們還是只打算去快樂地吞掉行星
There's a chance it'll just go on its merry planet-eating way.
我們的另一個選項是棄艦並使用穿梭機撤離
Our other option is to abandon ship and escape by shuttle.
我們可以派一架穿梭機到最近的子空間通訊中繼
We could take one to the nearest subspace relay
然後呼叫星際艦隊
and hail Starfleet.
等我們到的時候
By the time we get there,
沙利文星上的所有人早就死透了
everyone on Sullivan's Planet will be dead.
結論就是 兩個選擇都很災難
So we're agreed, both options are terrible,
但我們總得選一個 一個小時後他們就到那了
but we have to pick one. In one hour it'll be here.
我們只有一個小時來決定哪個更不災難一些
That's how long we've got to decide which is least terrible.
這也不是我們能決定的
That is not our decision to make.
我哪個都不選
I pick neither option.
好吧 那很勇敢了 而且 如果你不介意我這麼說的話
Okay. That is a bold and-- if you don't mind me saying--
簡直離譜到家了
highly unorthodox choice.
行了
Okay.
長官 他只是很擔心
Sir, he's just concerned.
他們還扣著我們的人
They have our crew,
而且正在前往一顆有人居住的行星
and the planet they're headed for is inhabited.
我們無法警告他們 除非
We won't be able to warn them without...
謝謝你 烏乎拉少尉
Thank you, Ensign Uhura.
我對情況很清楚
I'm up to speed on the particulars.
沒有進一步解釋的必要
No need for further discussion.
那我們怎麼給你選項呢
Then how will we provide you with options?
我不需要選項
I don't need options.
我不需要你們喋喋不休
I don't need chattering voices.
我現在需要清空頭腦
What I need is to clear my head.
但我現在沒辦法
And I can't do it with all this...
好吧 情況本來可以更好的
Well, that could have gone better.
不可能 怎麼可能
No. How?
這是他第一次坐艦長椅 是吧
This is his first time in the chair, right?
他以前也接管過指揮 但從來沒像這樣
He's had the conn before but never like this.
他表現出典型的受脅迫下的緊張跡象
He's showing classic signs of strain under duress.
他感受到的壓力肯定很
The pressure he must be feeling...
啊 太棒了 起初他還無所顧忌
Aye, great. First he's reckless,
現在他又要跟樹枝一樣一折就斷了
now he's liable to snap like a twig.
假設他真斷了 那怎麼樣 嗯
Let's say he does. What then, huh?
我們就要採取措施來
We would take steps to...
解除他的指揮權
remove him from command.
那 那些措施具體是什麼
And... what would those steps be, exactly?
作為艦上當前最高級別的醫療軍官
As ranking medical officer on board,
我有權評估他的健康狀況
it's within my power to evaluate him
並在他在心理上不適合的情況下 解除他的職務
and, if he is mentally unfit, remove him from duty.
好吧 在我們考慮這條路之前
Okay, before we even think about going down this road,
我們應該先考慮
we should consider
他還能工作 這只是他的風格
that he's still working on his command style.
對啊 現在他的風格是裝死
Aye. Right now his style is lacking.
這就是問題
That's my point.
我們或許可以幫助他找到方法
Maybe we can help him find it.
我以前見過他處理危機
I've seen him in a crisis before,
他沒有被迫當艦長的壓力的時候
when he didn't have the pressures of being captain.
他能看到連我都想不到的自己的潛力
He saw something in me that I hadn't seen in myself.
這救了我的命
It saved my life.
我覺得他只是需要有人提醒
I think he just needs to be reminded
他身上也有這種潛力
that same thing is in him.
那我們中就有人需要和他談談
Well, one of us should talk to him.
他很顯然很激動
He is clearly agitated.
或許風格更冷靜的人
Perhaps someone with a less emotional style
去和他談 會更有效果
might be more effective.
莫雷爾 撐住
Maurer... come on.
莫雷爾 清醒點
Maurer, stay with us.
來不及了  必須現在治療她
She can't wait. We have to treat her now.
現在 那兩個傢伙還在外面晃蕩呢
What, with those two things roaming around?
別無選擇了
We have no choice.
沒法對他們造成任何傷害
They're not taking any damage.
進這裡 左舷餐廳
In here, the Port Galley.
沒有毒氣 安全了
No fumes. We're safe.
她在大出血
She's bleeding out.
我需要醫療箱
I need a medkit.
等一下 我覺得
Wait, wait, wait, I think...
要是我們有通訊器和能用的傳送器
If we had comms and a functioning transporter,
是能救她的
we could have saved her.
未必 那些離子粒子
You don't know. Those ion particles
就像子彈一樣 能撕裂皮肉和骨骼
are like bullets. They rip through flesh and bone,
雖然原始 但殺傷力十足
primitive but effective.
可他們的防護服卻異常先進
And yet their suits are highly advanced.
我從沒見過能吸收相位槍火力的設備
I have never seen a device absorb phaser fire like that.
這不合常理
It doesn't make sense.
或許他們來自
Maybe they're from some
宇宙中某個永遠無法用常理解釋的陰暗角落
dark corner of the cosmos that'll never make sense.
我們得想辦法解決他們的護甲防禦
We have to find a way to get through their defenses somehow.
沒人見過他們 但我知道
No one has ever seen them, but I know
即便是戈恩人 也把他們視作怪物
they were considered monsters, even by the Gorn.
相位槍調至擊殺模式
Set phasers to kill.
這可是我從伊塞奈特釀酒廠進口的酒
I had this imported from an Ithenite distillery.
我會賠你一瓶的
I'll get you another one.
就像我的一位老朋友曾經說的
As an old friend of mine once said,
「要有光」
"Let there be light."
快點進來吧
Come, come, come.
她的艙室
Her quarters are...
和我想像中的一模一樣
exactly what I expected.
在這 不對 好了
Here. No, no. Okay.
在這裡
There you are.
不是你
Not you.
你以前倒是活潑
You were once bouncy
又開朗 可新鮮勁一過
and cheerful, but when the novelty wore off,
就有點嚇人了
you got a little creepy.
這些破爛玩意兒
How is any of this junk
怎麼幫我們飛離這裡啊
going to help us fly out of here?
我的老天
Oh, my goodness,
我以前就靠這個操控過不少星艦呢
I piloted many a starship with this.
雖然是8比特的船嘛
Granted, they were 8-bit,
但週五晚上玩這個還挺有意思的
but it was a good time on a Friday night.
啊 找到了
Ah, found it.
拿著
Take.
這該不會是
Is this a, uh,
個人按摩器吧
personal massager?
哦 這在以前可是最先進的通訊器
Oh, this was once a state-of-the-art communicator.
得插在牆上才能用
You had to plug it into the wall,
不過要是有人煩你 你就能讓他們一直等著
but if people annoyed you, you'd put them on hold.
應該還有更多的
I think there are more.
所以信號是通過有線傳輸的
So the signals are grounded,
從一根線纜直接傳到另一根線纜
transmitted cable to cable.
拿著那個
Take that.
這樣就能防止信號被干擾了
Which will insulate them from being jammed.
我們要讓船員們
We're going to have the crew
拆除船上所有的銅纜
strip the ship for copper cables,
然後給進取號重新布線
and we're going to wire the Enterprise.
快去吧
Go on.
我和維瑞爾艦長之前有一局棋沒下完
Captain V'Rel and I had an ongoing game.
那是我第一次覺得
For the first time, I think I was
自己快要贏她了
on my way to beating her,
可我們始終沒機會結束那局
but we never had the chance to finish.
我記得當時棋盤就擺成這樣
I think this is how we left the board.
恕我打擾
If I may interrupt.
哦 你已經打擾了
Oh, you already have.
別停
Don't stop now.
你否決了兩個有缺陷的方案
You rightly dismissed two flawed courses of action,
但時間緊迫 我們需要新計劃
but time is short and we require a new plan.
輪到維瑞爾走棋 我已經把她逼入絕境了
It was V'Rel's move, and I had her in a corner.
要是能想到她接下來會怎麼走就好了
If I could just figure out what she would have done next.
你現在是代理艦長 船員們都在等你
You are acting captain. Your crew is waiting.
讓他們等太久對事態
To keep them waiting longer would be...
沒有好處
...not good.
問題是
Here's the thing.
我慌了神
I'm frozen.
這倒讓我有點意外
I find this surprising.
你哥哥常說
Your brother speaks often
你一直想要指揮星艦
of your aspirations for command
也很有領導才能
and of your affinity for leadership.
其實他原話是
Actually, he said
你不管面對誰
you are not afraid to throw your weight around,
都敢直言發令 毫不含糊
no matter who's in front of you.
是啊 這倒像山姆會說的話
Yeah, that sounds like Sam.
某種程度上 他說得沒錯
And in a way he's right.
從我加入星艦學院那天起
From the moment I joined the Academy,
我就下定決心要比任何人都快地
I was determined to sit in that chair
坐上那把艦長椅
faster than anyone before me
因為我覺得自己比別人更懂行
because I thought I knew better.
覺得自己比別人更優秀
I thought I was better.
每當我覺得命令不合理時
Whenever orders don't make sense to me,
而且我總是覺得不合理
which happens more often than I'd like,
我總想 該由我來下達命令才對
I always think that I should be the one giving them.
之前 我讓維雷爾艦長派一支登陸小隊
Earlier, I told Captain V'Rel to send a landing party
去赫利孔γ星
to Helicon Gamma.
我當時極力勸說她
I pushed her hard on it.
還好她沒聽我的
Thank God she ignored me,
不然爆炸時 我們只能在地表等死
otherwise we'd all be standing on the surface when it exploded.
優秀的艦長知道該何時傾聽
Good leaders know when to listen
何時堅持己見
and when not to.
而我連這一點也沒做到
Well, I failed at that test, too.
斯科特先生也警告過我
Mr. Scott warned me
不要強行啟動引擎
not to push the engines,
可我還是命令他這麼做了
but I ordered him to anyway.
我這段時間一直憑直覺行事
I've been flying by the seat of my pants this whole time,
一次次做決定
making call after call
卻完全不知道這些決定會帶我們走向何方
with no clue where they'd lead us,
只能指望自己碰巧選對
hoping I'd luck into the right one,
結果卻讓我們困在這
and all I did was put us belly up in the path of
直面那個什麼終極毀滅者
the ultimate destroyer.
現在你確實陷入了信心危機
And now you are having a crisis of confidence,
但你還是得繼續領導大家
but you still have to lead.
說真的 我也想啊
Believe me, I'd love to,
可我現在完全沒頭緒
but there's nothing coming to me.
我媽媽常說一句話
My mom was fond of an expression.
「實現目標的人 往往不知道接下來該怎麼辦」
"The dog who caught the car."
如今我終於有了機會
Now that I've finally latched onto one...
卻不知道該怎麼應對
...I have no idea what to do with it.
在瓦肯星 我們也有一句類似的話
On Vulcan, we have a similar expression.
「咬到自己尾巴的賽拉獸」
"The sehlat who ate its tail."
不過我要指出 你比那種
Though I would point out you have
四足野獸有更多的優勢
a significant leg up over a quadrupedal beast.
你的人類直覺
Your human intuition.
它一直指引著我們 我們現在還都好好活著
It has guided us this far. We are all still here.
我建議你繼續相信它
I recommend you keep following it.
好的
Okay.
既然你這麼說
If you insist.
斯科提 那艘拾荒船還有多久到
Scotty, how long until that scavenger ship gets here?
不到 20 分鐘 但這只是估算
Less than 20 minutes, but that's just an estimate.
對我來說夠了
Well, it's good enough for me.
很高興看到你回來了 長官
Glad to see you back, sir.
我也是
Me, too.
我知道我們開局不順
Look, I know we got off to a rough start here,
我說什麼也彌補不了這一點
and there's nothing I can say that can make up for that.
而且激昂的演講也不是我的強項
Rousing speeches aren't exactly my forte.
長官 我覺得你說得很好
I think you're doing just fine, sir.
但我要跟在座各位說清楚
But let me be crystal clear to each of you.
即便我之前的行為讓你們有別的想法
Even if my actions indicated otherwise,
我也絕不會放棄營救進取號
I have no intention of giving up on rescuing the Enterprise,
畢竟我們兩隊船員的生命都危在旦夕
not with the lives of both of our crews on the line.
謝謝您 長官 我正需要聽到這句話
Thank you, sir. I needed to hear that.
我也需要聽聽你們的想法
And I need to hear from you.
我們現在掌握了什麼情況
What do we know?
除了我們困在太空中動彈不得之外
Besides the fact that we're dead in space,
關於這些拾荒者 我們還知道什麼
what do we know about these scavengers?
他們的船肯定有什麼弱點
Their ship has to have some kind of weakness.
烏乎拉 你觀察到了什麼
Uhura, what have you seen?
裡面有很多船
Ships, a lot of them,
來自象限的各個角落 它擄走船隻
from across the quadrant. It appropriates them,
竊取它們的能力
steals their functionality,
然後為己所用
and bends that to its own needs.
而且它的欲望永無止境
And its needs are bottomless.
它只懂得不斷吞噬 讓自己變得更大
All it does is consume and make itself bigger.
它變得越大 需要的就越多
The bigger it gets, the more it requires.
然後就會去吞噬下一個資源 就是
Then it moves on to devour the next resource, like...
它永遠不會停下
it will never stop,
它永遠不會滿足
you know, it'll never have enough.
沒錯 斯科提 你剛才已經找到了他們的弱點
Exactly. Scotty, you just found their weakness:
極度過分的吞噬欲
their ravenous need to consume.
無盡的貪慾
Bottomless greed.
我們可以利用這點來對抗它們
We can use that against them.
該怎麼做
How?
這就要輪到你出場了
That's where you come in.
我需要你用奧登金充滿等離子歧管
I need you to fill the plasma manifold
直到溢出為止
until it's overflowing with aldentium.
不 不 歧管只是個沒用的殼子
No-no, the-the manifold's a useless husk,
況且船上連一滴奧登金都沒有
and we don't have a drop of aldentium on board.
我們只需要讓它看起來像
We just need to make it look like we do.
隨著奧登金衰變
As aldentium decays,
這個過程中會釋放出很多反質子
it gives off lots of anti-protons.
我可以用反質子來填充混合室
Well, I could flood the intermix chamber with anti-protons
讓我們的引擎看起來像是由奧登金驅動的
and make it look like our engines run on aldentium.
它們會發現我們的蹤跡 被我們的排氣管吸引過來
They'll catch the scent and gravitate towards our tailpipe.
我們要把法拉格特號
We are going to make the Farragut
偽裝成一場令拾荒者垂涎欲滴的盛宴
into a banquet that's impossible for these scavengers to resist,
當它們來赴宴時
and when they come to dine,
就該後悔得腸子都青了
we're going to make them regret it.
艦長已經下令了
The captain has given his orders.
我還是覺得這麼叫怪怪的 維瑞爾還活著呢
I still feel funny being called that while V'Rel's alive.
我保證一有機會就會盡快給你降職
I promise to demote you at the earliest opportunity.
等等 所以在這些拾荒者嘗試吃掉我們的時候 我們又該怎麼辦
Wait, so what exactly do we do after we get these scavengers to try and eat us?
這就是這個計劃有點瘋狂的地方了
Here's where the plan gets a little crazy.
什麼這個計劃有點瘋狂的地方
This is where the plan gets crazy?
幸好你正坐著呢 查普爾護士
Glad you're sitting down, Nurse Chapel.
尤其是你 斯考特先生
You especially, Mr. Scott,
你不會喜歡這個的
are not going to love it.
拉安
La'An!
警告 環境指標危險
你還好嗎
You all right?
還好
Yeah.
它沒有開槍
It... didn't shoot.
為什麼它不殺了我
Why didn't it kill me?
我們可能只有一分鐘的時間
We may only have a minute.
該怎麼把這死東西從我的船上弄下來
How do we get this thing the hell off my ship?
如果我們不能切斷它 那麼說服它們呢
Well, if we can't disconnect it, what if we convince them to?
-什麼意思 -讓它們自願斷開連接
- How do you mean? - Make them want to disconnect it.
讓它們嚐到點
Give them a taste of something...
難吃的東西
highly undesirable.
我懂了 讓它覺得反胃酸了
I see, stir up a little acid reflux?
是的
Yeah.
重子粒子如何
What about, uh, baryon particles?
那它們的燃料和美好的一天就都該完蛋了
That would ruin their fuel and their day.
我們其中一個必須進入曲速引擎下面的
One of us would have to access the waste system
廢物處理系統
beneath the warp drive.
廢物處理系統 好吧 你去吧
Waste system? All right, you do that.
我得把燃料管道隔離
I have to isolate the fuel line.
還有  拿一個超耦合器過來
And bring a hyper coupler.
拉安
La'An
小心點 還有一個外星人活著
Be careful, that other alien's still out there.
女士們 上次我幹這種話
Ladies, I haven't done this
還是給死人樂隊打雜的時候呢
since I was a roadie for the Dead.
你這個種族還可以和死人交流嗎
Your species can communicate with dead people?
你好
Hello?
是的 是的
Ah, ah, yes, yes.
上尉 找你的
Uh, uh, Lieutenant, it's for you.
喂
Hello?
右舷推進器已經準備好了
Starboard thrusters are ready.
左舷推進器也準備就緒
Port thrusters standing by.
好吧 艾麗卡 小心別墜機
Okay, Erica, don't crash.
拾荒者星艦已脫離曲速
The scavenger vessel has dropped out of warp.
反質子 正在反著質子
Anti-protons... anti-protoning?
我們現在已經美味到極限了
We're as juicy a target as I can make us.
紅色警報 各崗位準備
Red alert. All stations prepare for...
好吧 準備被吃
...well, for that.
脈衝引擎準備
Ready impulse engines.
已就緒
Standing by.
她掌舵過多少次
How many times has she helmed?
兩次 包括這次
Twice, including now.
脈衝全速 烏乎拉
Full impulse, Uhura.
斯考提 輪到你了
Scotty, your turn.
如果你堅持的話
If you insist.
我堅持 斯考特先生
I do, Mr. Scott.
聽我口令分離
Detach at my mark.
分離
Mark.
史波克
Spock?
貪吃蛇咬到自己尾巴了 艦長
The sehlat has eaten its tail, Captain.
拾荒者星艦已被癱瘓
The scavenger ship has been disabled.
烏乎拉 盡快找到進取號
Uhura, get us line of sight to the Enterprise as quickly as you can.
接收到信號傳輸
Incoming transmission.
是法拉格特號 僅音頻
It's the Farragut, audio only.
進取號 能收到嗎
Enterprise, do you read?
可算來了啊 少尉
Took you long enough, Ensign.
我也很高興聽到你的聲音
Good to hear your voice, too.
我們受損嚴重 但是我們已經癱瘓了拾荒者星艦
We're pretty banged up, but we disabled the scavenger ship.
告訴她這只是暫時的
Tell her it's just temporary.
能持續多久
How temporary?
不清楚 但這是你們的機會
No idea, but this is your chance.
越獄的機會
For a jailbreak.
左 右舷推進器
Port and starboard thrusters,
百分之十動力
give me ten percent.
我們得關閉推進器 我們還沒脫離束縛
we got to kill those thrusters. We are not off-leash.
艦長 找到燃料線路了嗎
Captain, any luck finding the fuel line?
我有一個相當可靠的猜測
I've got a pretty solid guess.
把那個連接器遞給我
Hand me that connector?
你最好後退一步
And you might want to take a step back.
如果爆炸 整個工程部船體都會被炸掉
If it explodes, it will take out the entire engineering hull.
多退幾步吧
A big step, then?
重子粒子正在進入氘粒子流
Baryon particles are entering the deuterium stream.
混合物 正在失去穩定
The mixture is... destabilizing.
趁我們還沒被這東西吸走
Let's get the hell out of here
趕緊跑路吧
before we get sucked out with this thing.
等等
Wait.
緊急系統正在重啟
Emergency systems are rebooting.
艦長做到了 這些臍帶正在脫離
Captain did it. The umbilical's detached.
左 右舷推進器
Port and starboard thrusters,
百分之五十
50%.
右舷推進器減緩點
Ease off starboard thrusters. Whoa.
別減這麼多 給我百分之三十
N-Not that easy. Give me 30%.
百分之五十 現在等下
50%. Now wait.
五十 八十
50, 80.
切斷右舷推進器
Cut starboard thrusters.
我也不想說風涼話 但是你要撞牆
Hate to backseat-drive, but you're hitting the wall.
左舷推進器全速
Full port thrusters.
推進器控制無響應
Thruster controls aren't responding.
這要完蛋了
That's real bad.
等等 我有個想法
Wait, I have an idea.
洗耳恭聽
I'm all ears.
中校?
Commander?
好 右舷推進器動力20%
Yes! Starboard thrusters to 20%.
保持平衡
Keep us even.
艦長
Captain.
是拾荒者
The scavenger.
拾荒者星艦的系統正在恢復運行
The scavenger vessel's systems are coming back on line.
他們正在瞄準進取號
They are targeting Enterprise.
相位炮鎖定
Lock phasers.
呃
Uh...
艦長 我們的武器無法
Sir, the grapplers have proven
有效應對那些抓鈎
to be resistant to our weapons.
好吧 史波克
Okay, Spock.
你有什麼主意嗎
What do you got?
史波克先生 掃描殘骸中的生命信號
Mr. Spock, scan the debris for life signs.
近7000個生命信號
Approximately 7,000 life signs,
在迅速減少
but they are dwindling quickly.
我們能把生還者傳送到船上嗎
Can we beam survivors aboard?
我們有心無力
Not even if we wanted to.
殘骸的碎片會影響傳送器 無法鎖定
There's too much debris to get a transporter lock.
艦長
Captain?
那些生命信號
The life signs.
是的 史波克先生
Yes, Mr. Spock?
那些生命信號全都是人類
The life signs are all human.
船體上的標記
The markings on the hull.
我們能看得更清楚一點嗎
Can you get us a clearer image?
好的
Aye.
我在歷史數據庫裡找到了這個
I found this in our historical database.
21世紀中期
In the mid-21st century,
在與瓦肯人的第一次接觸之前
before first contact with the Vulcans,
有一群科學家 他們認為
a group of scientists believed
岌岌可危的地球環境
that Earth's environmental crisis was too severe
沒有復原的可能 所以他們建造了一艘飛船
to recover from, so they built a ship.
他們希望這艘船能讓人類文明
They hoped it would carry humanity
在其他世界中繼續生根發芽
to civilizations in other worlds.
但事與願違
But it failed.
這艘船消失了
The ship disappeared.
全體船員
The entire crew,
他們的家人 都消失了
their families, gone.
此後音訊全無
Never heard from again.
我還記得這艘船發射升空時的事
I remember when it launched.
那時我們還沒有發明曲速引擎
We-we hadn't yet invented warp drive.
第三次世界大戰才堪堪結束
We'd barely put out the fires of the Third World War.
熬過戰爭的國家不多 其中一個
One of the few nations left standing
在他們殘存的航天計劃中挑選
sifted through the ashes of their space program,
走遍全世界招募了一批船員
scoured the world for a crew.
可以說
You might say...
那是當年最出類拔萃的一批人
...they were the best of us,
最為樂觀積極
the most optimistic,
他們拚盡全力尋找
searching for a way to carry on
延續文明之火的方式
the flame of life.
那麼多船員
All those people.
7000條生命
7,000 souls.
他們是初始船員們的後人
The descendants of the original inhabitants.
到底出了什麼差錯
So what went wrong?
他們為什麼會從那樣一批優秀的船員變成
How did they go from that to...
現在這個樣子
...whatever it is they became?
請進
Come in.
啊
Ah...
只是想當面告訴你
Just wanted to let you know in person,
姆'本加醫生說維瑞爾艦長
Dr. M'Benga says that Captain V'Rel is going
之後會完全康復的
to make a complete recovery.
我們會把法拉格特號拖回船塢
We'll tow Farragut back to spacedock.
你只需要
Then you only have
再撐一會兒就好
to hold the fort down a little while longer.
拖回去一艘沒了曲速艙的船
I'm imagining the look on Admiral April's face
我幾乎都能想像到艾普里爾上將的表情了
when he sees us pull in with no nacelles.
他喜歡畢宿五威士忌
He likes Aldebaran whiskey.
備好一瓶以備不時之需
Maybe have a bottle ready.
可能你會覺得很難受 但你確實做出了正確的決定
You know, it might not feel like it, but you made the right call.
我們遭到了攻擊
We were under attack.
你拯救了幾百條生命 法拉格特號上的和進取號上的
You saved hundreds of lives, both here and on Enterprise.
未知船隻
Number of...
上的預估傷亡人數是
estimated human casualties on unknown vessel...
七千
...7,000.
我可以坐下嗎
Well, may I?
請坐
Please.
你知道 我剛晉升
You know, when, uh...
為大副的時候
when I got bumped up to first officer,
我記得我經常懷疑鮑勃
I remember second-guessing Bob--
就是艾普里爾上將
uh, Admiral April-- a lot.
難道他沒有為此糾正你的想法嗎
Did he ever straighten you out?
沒有
No.
他給了我一個深刻的教訓
He let me learn a very hard lesson.
重大的決定背後需要肩負的責任
The big decisions-- they seem so simple
只有在別人身上才看起來輕鬆
when someone else has to live with the consequences,
但當你坐在艦長的位置上 作出的每一個決定
but the choices you make in that chair...
都是你需要肩負的責任
...they are yours to make...
其後果
...and what comes after...
也是你必須承擔的
...that is yours to live with.
有一些決定會讓你悔恨終生
Some decisions you will regret for the rest of your life,
但你仍然不得不去做
but you still have to make them.
那些人都是人類
They were human beings.
為什麼我會覺得更難受了
Why does that make it feel so much worse?
我能說的只有
All I can say is...
同情你的敵人是工作時的必經之途
...having empathy for your adversary is part of the job.
但我沒有
But I didn't.
我沒想過他們會是人類
I didn't think of them as people...
從頭到尾
at all.
然後一切都無法挽回了
Until it was too late.
也許這正是我們應當反思的
Well, maybe that's the lesson.
同情是不看對象的
Empathy isn't conditional.
有就是有 沒有就是沒有
It's either given or it isn't.
他們肯定看見了我們的模樣
They... clearly saw us,
要麼他們沒有認出我們 要麼他們不在乎
and either they didn't recognize us or they didn't care.
無論過去兩百年
Whatever journey they had been through
發生了什麼 他們已經不是當初的那批船員了
the last 200 years, it broke them.
他們離開地球的時候
When they left Earth...
是全人類中最優秀的
...they were the best humanity had to offer.
他們過去並不是怪物
They weren't monsters.
我們在同樣的情況下也會變成那樣嗎
Is that what we would become in the same circumstances?
我想我們不會的
I'd like to believe we wouldn't.
為什麼
Why not?
因為我們對他們懷有同情
Because of how you're feeling right now.
因為下一次你作為艦長下達指令的時候
Because the next time you're in that chair,
你會想起我們與我們的敵人
you will remember we are often not that different
並沒有那麼不同
from our enemy.
這種認識
And that knowledge,
從現在起
from this moment on,
會永遠指引著你
will continue to guide you.
晚安 柯克艦長
Good night, Captain Kirk.